So, you have a sense of what the PCs are.
你已经知道 PC 是什么
Now, I have an important thing to tell you about how we use them.
下面我将讲解关于如何使用 PC 的重要概念
In fact, we frequently don't use all the PCs.
实际上 我们通常并不使用所有 PC
Instead, we decide to use some fraction of them starting with the first,
只是使用部分 PC 并且从第一个 PC 开始
which we think explain most of the variance,
我们认为它能解释方差的大部分
and I'm going to explain what I mean by that in a moment.
稍后我会解释这句话的意思
So, for example, with the 2D dataset I'm showing you here,
例如 对于这个二维数据集
if we decide to only use the first PC,
如果我们决定只使用第一个 PC
instead of an x-coordinate and a y-coordinate for each data point,
而不使用每个数据点的 x 坐标和 y 坐标
we just use a single coordinate that represents how
我们仅使用一个坐标
far along the first basis dimension the point falls.
它表示点与第一个基向量维度的距离
This is a lower dimensional representation of the same dataset and it
这是同一数据集的低维表示法
makes the most sense if the data approximately fall along a line to begin with.
如果数据近似地沿着一条线分布 这种方法最合理
In this new representation,
在这个新表示法中
we lose the information about how far
我们丢失了关于原始数据点
the original data points lie in the direction perpendicular to the first PC.
与第一个 PC 垂直的方向的距离这一信息
However, if those distances are small,
但是 如果这些距离很小
we don't lose much information.
并没有丢失多少信息
But if we have many dimensions to begin with,
如果数据有很多维度
how do we decide how many PCs to use?
如何决定要使用多少个 PC？
Well, it can depend on the application,
这取决于具体应用
but one way is by calculating how much variance each of
但一种方法是计算每个 PC 能解释的方差量
the PCs account for and by dropping those that account for the least variance.
并丢弃解释方差量最少的 PC
That seems reasonable, but how do we implement that quantitatively?
似乎比较合理 但是如何定量实施呢？
Well, we know that the variance along each dimension is an important quantity in PCA.
我们知道沿着每个维度的方差在 PCA 中是很重要的量
It turns out that the total variance is the
实际上 原始基向量下的总方差
same in the original basis as it is in the new basis.
等于新基向量下的总方差
Let me explain what I mean by that.
我来解释下
Let's start with the three data points we had before,
先从之前已有的三个数据点开始
where we've already mean centered the data.
这些数据点已经均值居中
The variance along the original horizontal dimension
沿着原始水平维度的方差
is the sum of the squares of these lengths.
等于这些长度的平方和
The variance along the original vertical dimension
沿着原始垂直维度的方差
But because of the Pythagorean theorem,
根据勾股定理
the sum of the squares of all of these lengths equals the sum of
所有这些长度的平方和等于
the squares of the distances from the origin to each data point.
每个点到原点的距离的平方和
When we find the new PC basis,
当我们找到新的 PC 基向量时
we can calculate the variances along the new dimensions.
我们可以计算沿着新维度的方差
But since each dimension is still orthogonal to every other dimension,
但是因为每个维度依然与其他维度正交
we still have that the sum of the variances in
所以每个维度的方差之和
each dimension equals the squared distance to each data point from the origin.
依然等于每个点到原点的距离平方
Since the sum of the variance of
因为所有数据点的方差之和
all the data points is determined by their distance from the center,
由它们到中心的距离决定
the sum of total variance is the same,
所以总方差之和不变
regardless of which basis you choose.
无论你选择哪种基向量
This quantity, the sum of the squares of
这个量 即每个数据点
the distances to each data point from the origin,
到原点的距离平方和
is called the total variance of the data.
称为数据的总方差
As you have already seen,
你已经知道
each principal component, that is,
每个主成分
each new dimension for the data,
即数据的每个新维度
is associated with some fraction of the total variance.
都关联总方差的一部分
The first PC is associated with the most,
第一个 PC 关联最多的方差
the second with the next most,
第二个 PC 关联次多的方差
and so on down the line.
以此类推
So, in order to decide how many PCs to keep,
为了决定要保留多少个 PC
we might look at the variance of the data along
我们可以看看数据沿着每个维度的方差
each dimension and drop the dimensions along which the data vary the least.
并丢弃数据沿着它变化最小的维度
It is in this sense that PCA is used as a dimensional reduction algorithm.
从这个角度来说 PCA 是一种降维算法
When we drop the dimensions that capture less of the spread of the data,
当我们丢弃只能解释很少的数据差异的维度时
we have lost some information,
我们丢弃了一些信息
but retained most of the spread and thus most of the information.
但是保留了大部分差异 所以保留了大部分信息